YOONJOO LEE

yoonjoo.lee@kaist.ac.kr | yoonjoolee.com

RESEARCH INTEREST

My research interest lies in the intersection of human-computer interaction (HCI) and natural language processing (NLP). I aim to support adaptive and personalized language design by structuring the information embedded in language in a way that aligns with human cognition, characteristics, and behavior. Through these structures, I seek to enable AI models to understand individual users in relation to language and to then generate language that is more suited to their states and needs.

EDUCATION

KAIST Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Ph.D. Candidate in Computer Science. Advisor: Juho Kim

Sep. 2020 – Present

Ewha Womans University Seoul, Republic of Korea

M.S. in Statistics (Applicational Statistics). Advisor: Dongwan Shin

Mar. 2018 – Feb. 2020

B.S. Major in Mathematics Education, Minor in Statistics; *Magna Cum Laude*Mar. 2014 – Feb. 2018

University of California, Davis

Davis, CA, USA

Exchange student in Mathematics Sep. 2015 – Feb. 2016

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Allen Institute for AI (AI2) Seattle, US

Research Scientist Intern, Semantic Scholar Team

May - Oct. 2023

Mentor: Pao Siangliulue, Joseph Chee Chang, Jonathan Bragg, Kyle Lo [C10]

LG AI Research Seoul, Republic of Korea

Research Scientist Intern, Advanced Machine Learning Lab
Mentor: Moontae Lee, Kyungjae Lee
[C6]

KIXLAB, KAIST Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Graduate Research Intern
Mar. 2020 – Aug. 2020

Mentor: Juho Kim, Jean Y. Song

Electronics and Telecommunications Research Institute (ETRI)

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Graduate Research Assistant, Data Sciences Group

Mar. 2018 – Dec. 2019

[P1. P2. C1. C2]

Mentor: Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park [P1, P2, C1, C2]

PUBLICATIONS

Conference and Journal Papers

[C11] One vs. Many: Comprehending Accurate Information from Multiple Erroneous and Inconsistent AI Generations

Yoonjoo Lee, Kihoon Son, Tae Soo Kim, Jisu Kim, John Joon Young Chung, Eytan Adar, Juho Kim *Under review, 2024*

[C10] PaperWeaver: Enriching Topical Paper Alerts by Contextualizing Recommended Papers with User-collected Papers

Yoonjoo Lee, Hyeonsu B Kang, Matt Latzke, Juho Kim, Jonathan Bragg, Joseph Chee Chang, Pao Siangliulue *Accepted in CHI 2024*

[C9] EvalLM: Interactive Evaluation of Large Language Model Prompts on User-Defined Criteria

Tae Soo Kim, **Yoonjoo Lee**, Jamin Shin, Young-Ho Kim, Juho Kim *Accepted in CHI 2024*

[C8] VIVID: Human-AI Collaborative Authoring of Vicarious Dialogues from Lecture Videos

Seulgi Choi, Hyewon Lee, **Yoonjoo Lee**, Juho Kim *Accepted in CHI 2024*

[C7] QASA: Advanced Question Answering on Scientific Articles

Yoonjoo Lee*, Kyungjae Lee*, Sunghyun Park, Dasol Hwang, Jaehyeon Kim, Hong-in Lee, Moontae Lee *ICML 2023: Proceedings of the 40th International Conference on Machine Learning*

[C6] Cells, Generators, and Lenses: Design Framework for Object-Oriented Interaction with Large Language Models

Tae Soo Kim, Yoonjoo Lee, Minsuk Chang, Juho Kim

UIST 2023: Proceedings of the 2023 ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (to appear).

[C5] DAPIE: Interactive Step-by-Step Explanatory Dialogues to Answer Children's Why and How Questions

Yoonjoo Lee, Tae Soo Kim, Sundong Kim, Yohan Yun, Juho Kim

CHI 2023: Proceedings of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems.

[C4] Promptiverse: Scalable Generation of Scaffolding Prompts Through Human-AI Hybrid Knowledge Graph Annotation

Yoonjoo Lee, John Joon Young Chung, Tae Soo Kim, Jean Y. Song, Juho Kim

CHI 2022: Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems

[C3] Personalizing Ambience and Illusionary Presence: How People Use "Study with Me" Videos to Create Effective Studying Environments

Yoonjoo Lee, John Joon Young Chung, Jean Y. Song, Minsuk Chang, Juho Kim

CHI 2021: Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems.

[C2] A Machine Learning Approach that meets Axiomatic Properties in Probabilistic Analysis of LTE Spectral Efficiency

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park

ICTC, Oct. 2019

[C1] Probabilistic Analysis of Spectral Efficiency for LTE based on PDCCH Measurement Data

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Yeonkyu Park, Seungken Park

IEEE Communications Letters, vol. 23, no. 9, Sep. 2019

Posters and Workshop Papers

[P5] LMCanvas: Object-Oriented Interaction to Personalize Large Language Model-Powered Writing Environments

Tae Soo Kim, Arghya Sarkar, Yoonjoo Lee, Minsuk Chang, and Juho Kim

CHI 2023 Workshop on Generative AI and HCI

[P4] Interactive Children's Story Rewriting Through Parent-Children Interaction

Yoonjoo Lee, Tae Soo Kim, Minsuk Chang, Juho Kim

ACL 2022 Workshop on Intelligent and Interactive Writing Assistant

[P3] XDesign: Integrating Interface Design into Explainable AI Education

Hyungyu Shin, Nabila Sindi, **Yoonjoo Lee**, Jaeryoung Ka, Jean Y. Song, Juho Kim *SIGCSE TS 2022 Posters*

[P2] A Study on the Distribution Analysis of LTE Resource Block Usage from TSME Measurement Data

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park

KICS, Jun. 2018

[P1] A Study on the Estimation of Probability Distribution of the Spectral Efficiency of LTE based on TSME Measurement Data

Yunbae Kim, Yoonjoo Lee, Seungken Park

KICS, Jun. 2018

ACADEMIC SERVICES

Program Committee

• CHI LBW 2023

Workshop Organizing Committee

• 2024 ACL Science Document Processing Workshop

Reviewer

- EMNLP 2023
- CHI 2024, 2023, 2022
- UIST 2022, 2023
- ACL 2023
- CSCW 2023
- C&C 2022, 2024
- IEEE Transactions on Learning Technologies

Student Volunteer

CHI 2022

TEACHING

Introduction to Algorithms Spring 2024

KAIST CS300, Instructor: Sunghee Choi

Introduction to Data Science Spring 2022

KAIST CS492, Instructor: Jaegil Lee

Introduction to Social Computing Fall 2020, Fall 2021

KAIST CS473, Instructor: Juho Kim

Time Series Analysis Spring 2019

Ewha Womans University, Instructor: Dongwan Shin

Regression Analysis Fall 2018

Ewha Womans University, Instructor: Donghwan Lee

INVITED TALKS Invited Talk at HCI KOREA 2024: SIGCHI-Sponsored Top Conferences Session Jan. 2024 Title: DAPIE: Interactive Step-by-step Explanatory Dialogues to Answer Children's Why and How Questions Technical Talk at NAVER AI LAB Nov. 2023 Title: Creating Interactive Dialogues to Answer Children's Why and How Questions **Invited Talk at UCSD Design Lab** Oct. 2023 Title: Adapting Scaffolding to Support Knowledge Consumption through Interactive AI-Driven Systems HONORS, AWARDS, AND SCHOLARSHIPS **Best Presentation Award from SIGCHI Invited Papers Session** 2024 SIGCHI Korea Local Chapter 2019 Research Assistant Scholarship College of Natural Sciences, Ewha Womans University 2018 **Admission Scholarship** College of Natural Sciences, Ewha Womans University **Honors Scholarship** 2014, 2015, 2016, 2017 College of Education, Ewha Womans University Dean's List 2014, 2015, 2016, 2017 College of Education, Ewha Womans University **Ewha Womans University Alumnae Association Scholarship** 2017 College of Education, Ewha Womans University

SERVICE AND LEADERSHIP

KAIST-Google ExploreCSR
Student Organizer

2022

Programming Mentoring
Leader of Student Organizer

2016 – 2017